Kyle Dean

6 Hornsea Close, Oldham, Greater Manchester, OL9 0PY

07834281669 | kyle.antony.dean@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kdean7 | https://www.kyledean.dev

PROFILE

Enthusiastic and flexible student offering a wealth of experience and education in technical troubleshooting and problem-solving issues. I have over 6 years of experience with programming and digital design to bring to any team. Hard-working, educated, and willing to go the extra mile to complete any task.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Sheffield Hallam University | BSc Computer Science

Sep 2019 - Expected 2022

Modules I have passed and studying include (but not limited to): Professional Experience, Databases, Mobile Development, Object-oriented Programming, Fundamentals of Programming, Algorithms and Data structures, Fundamentals of Computer architecture

Oldham College | Advanced Technical Extended Diploma

Sep 2017 - May 2019

Level 3 Application Development - Distinction, Distinction

Core Maths - B

Pearson Extended Project - D

I studied a wide range of development skills, such as professional practices in the workplace, fundamentals of programming in VB.NET & C#, as well as design practices which focuses on the UI & UX properties that a good piece of software should entail to meet the client's needs.

Also, I chose to study two extra modules at college. Core maths was valuable in the practice of statistics & real-life use of mathematics, but also taught me to be much more logical in my thinking. The other module I studied was the Extended Project. This was a university standard piece of dissertation work, of which I chose to focus my writing on AI, delving into machine learning; discussing the possible benefits and drawbacks associated with the technology. This gave me great understanding and experience on the type of work expected at a higher level, also giving me the presentation skills needed in a workplace, as that was part of the final assignment.

Newman RC College | GCSEs

Sep 2012 - Jun 2017

Achieved 9 GCSEs grades A-B, including Mathematics, English, and Computer Science.

KEY SKILLS

- Cooperated with members of a team to plan & complete tasks to meet deadlines
- Aware of body language when listening and talking to a team member or supervisor
- Concise & literate in my vocabulary

DEVELOPMENT & IT SKILLS

- Familiar with frameworks such as jQuery, Bootstrap, React, .NET
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, VB.NET, C#
- Competent in Python, C, C++, Java, SQL
- Experienced use of the Windows operating system, Microsoft Office Suite & Git
- Knowledgeable use of Visual Files

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bar Staff | CODE Nightclub

Jun 2021 - Present

CODE is a reputable nightclub in Sheffield.

- Volunteered and worked as a team to manage incoming stock during the day
- Assisted supervisors with closing, cleaning, and managing stock at the end of the night
- Helped with setting up an outdoor festival site to then work on the bars
- Developed my communication skills further whilst working directly with customers
- Taught colleagues how to use tills and what steps to take in numerous situations
- Encouraged team members when faced with a high volume of customers

Customer Team Member | Co-op Food

Mar 2020 - Jun 2020

Co-op Food is a well-known food retail business.

- Worked as a team to manage the stock on the shop floor
- Listened to customer needs and used my knowledge to assist them
- Used the Deliveroo control panel to pick incoming orders
- Worked on the tills to assist customers with shopping and lottery tickets
- · Helped to establish Deliveroo orders at the branch
- Assisted colleagues with using the technology to pick online orders
- Taught colleagues how to mitigate issues with online order picking

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

I have a personal portfolio website which is live, but I am in the process of redesigning it with better UI/UX and better technology such as React to make it much more scalable for tablet and mobile devices.

Also, I have been working through the Harvard CS50 course online to sharpen my skills and broaden my knowledge on Computer Science, as well as mobile (using React) & web development.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Passionate football fan, and a club captain at a young age which taught me how to effectively communicate and show leadership. Although I do not get to play as much as I would like to at this stage but given the chance, I would get straight back into it.

In my spare time, I own and manage a game server and community which gives me a chance to take a break from work and talk to friends whilst learning valuable Java development and server infrastructure skills along the way.

I have a keen eye for digital design and often find myself watching and listening to tutorials on how to improve the UI/UX of any projects I might be working on.

REFERENCES

Soyful Islam | Digital & Creative Tutor at Oldham College - soyful.islam@oldham.ac.uk

Sam Clowes | Assistant Manager at CODE Nightclub - sam@codesheffield.com